想在此处添加您的广告信息？立即联系 www.OpenSubtitles.org
吸血鬼
日记
第六季 第二十一集
翻译 草草   胖兔纯   木浅薰   米苏   后期 鱼骨头
时间轴 JimmyBeck   大水   紫薰   校对 米苏   总监 米苏
《吸血鬼日记》前情提要
Previously on "The Vampire Diaries"...
治愈吸血鬼的解药
The cure to vampirism.
你要服下解药  埃琳娜
You're gonna take the cure, Elena.
我要和你一起服下
And I'm gonna take it with you.
但我不能让你这么做
but I can't let you do this,
你得先让你生命中的每个人
before you've let everyone in your life
劝你别这么做
try to talk you out of it.
-我怀孕了  -嫁给我
- I'm pregnant. - Marry me.
我愿意
Yes.
如果我的人性恢复时
If my life is gonna fall apart
我的人生要全面崩溃
when my humanity starts flooding back,
那么你也得一样
then so is yours.
我试图杀你
I tried to kill you,
然后我逼你关闭人性
and then I made you turn it off,.
我毁了一切
I ruined everything.
20世纪前  莉莉和一群被双子巫师团
Before the 1900s, Lily fell in with a group of witches
驱逐的巫师走到了一起
that were cast out of the Gemini Coven.
异教徒很残忍
Heretics are ruthless,
既是吸血鬼  又拥有巫师法力
vampires with witch power.
绝不能让他们逃出来
They can never be allowed to escape.
我们该离开这个鬼地方了
It's time we get the hell out of this place.
你昨晚大开杀戒了
You went off the deep end last night.
我现在简直一团糟
I'm a mess.
你根本不知道崩溃是什么感觉
You have no idea what devastation feels like,
但你会知道的
but you will.
埃琳娜
Elena?
又见面了  邦妮
Hello again, Bonnie.
莉莉  斯特凡不是把你锁在地下室了吗
Lily. I thought Stefan locked you in the cellar.
是啊  但逃狱是很容易的
He did, but prisons are easily escaped.
这你是最清楚的
You of all people should know that.
你想怎么样
What do you want?
我非得不断重复吗
Must I constantly repeat myself?
如果你到现在还不知道我想要什么
If you don't know what I want by now--
你要你可怕的吸血鬼巫师家族回到身边
You want your creepy witch vampire family back.
那我也重复一遍  休想
Well, at the risk of repeating myself, there's no way.
是吗  你们巫师
Isn't there? What's that term
最喜欢的那个词怎么说的来着  "漏洞"
you witches are so fond of? "Loophole"?
就算真有漏洞
Even if there is a loophole,
我也不会帮你找到
I won't help you find it.
你已经表明立场了
Oh, you've made your position quite clear.
显然  我并未好好表明我的立场
Apparently, I failed to do the same,
因为你似乎是以为我是来找你帮忙的
because you seem to think that I'm here for your help.
不是的
I'm not.
[咒语]
Phesmatos incendia.
好甜蜜的话语  邦妮
Those are lovely words, Bonnie.
再说一个  死吧
Here's another one--die.
你真不擅长跑啊
You are not good at running.
[咒语]
Motus.
没有魔法吗  我的错
No magic? Oh, that's my fault.
我刚刚抱着你睡来着
I was spooning you earlier.
可能在睡梦中把你吸干了
I think I might've sleep-siphoned you.
继续努力啊  挺可爱的
Oh, but keep trying. It's adorable,
像是癫痫了一样
like you're having a little seizure.
-你怎么...  -你真以为
- How are you-- - Did you think
你可以这么坑人
you could keep screwing people over
而不会有后果吗
and there wouldn't be any consequences?
好了
Now...
我们刚刚说到哪了
Where were we?
起床了  没时间睡懒觉了
Up, up, up. Come on. No time to sleep in.
我们得去接乔
We have to get Jo.
-接乔  -是啊
- Get Jo? - Yeah.
出什么事了吗
Is everything ok?
希望没有  再过10小时
I hope so, considering she's walking down the aisle
她就要嫁人了
in T-minus 10 hours.
走吧
Come on.
婚礼钟声要敲响了
Wedding bells await.
该死
Crap.
他们不在这儿
They're not here.
怎么了
What's wrong?
我的鞋  我美丽  贵得离谱
My shoes. My gorgeous, ridiculously expensive,
只穿一次就再也不碰的鞋子  不见了
wear them once and then never again shoes. They are missing.
要我施个定位咒找找吗
Do you want me to do a locator spell on them?
找我的鞋吗
On my shoes?
-这能做到吗  -不知道啊
- Is that possible? - I don't know, actually.
等等的  我看看怎么操作这破玩意
Just hang on. I got to figure out how to work this stupid thing.
好啊  弄坏吧
Oh, good. Break it
如果我裙子皱巴巴的
Because my wrinkled dress will surely
大家一定就不会注意到我没穿鞋了
distract everyone from my bare feet.
被这样  别现在就慌张啊
Come on. Don't waste all your panic now.
距离婚礼还有8小时呢
You still have 8 hours until the ceremony.
来杯不含酒精的含羞草吧
Non-alcoholic mimosa?
一  不含酒精的话  那就剩橙汁了
One, a non-alcoholic mimosa is just orange juice,
二  我不能喝东西
and two, I can't drink.
该有人喝酒  你喝吧
Somebody should drink. You should drink.
我回头会喝的
I will drink, eventually,
但我的酒量恢复人类状态了
But I have human tolerance now,
虽然省钱  但不那么好玩了
which is cheaper but a lot less fun.
干杯
Cheers.
别别
No, no, no, no.
放松
Relax.
乔的手机
Jo's phone.
好吧
Uh, ok.
这可不是没事的"好吧"
That's not an "ok" ok.
这是"有麻烦了"的"好吧"
That's a "there's a problem" ok.
我们再打给你  好的  再见
Yeah, we'll call you back. Ok, bye.
丹妮尔得了流感
Danielle's got the flu.
你好像刚刚说丹妮尔得了流感
It sounded like you just said Danielle has the flu,
这是不可能的  因为丹妮尔是我的婚礼协调人
which is impossible because Danielle is my wedding coordinator.
是啊
Yeah.
她病得多重  能继续工作吗
Well, how sick is she? Can she still work?
那要看你想在婚礼上看到多少呕吐物了
It depends on how much vomit you want to have at the wedding.
老实说  我觉得这或许也是好事
To be honest, I think maybe this is a good thing,
因为不管丹妮尔多厉害
Because no matter how good Danielle was,
都绝对比不过我
I am pretty sure I'm better.
卡罗琳
Caroline.
我好想你
I missed you.
我也想我了
I missed me, too.
谢谢你把我拉回来
Thank you for getting me back.
好了  我们有好多事要做
Ok. Now, we got a lot to do
却没多少时间
and not a lot of time to do it.
埃琳娜  喝一杯吧
Elena, just have a drink.
你不会昏过去的
You're not going to pass out.
邦妮  开关在左后方
Bonnie, the switch is on the left-hand side on the back.
乔  你的鞋就在沙发下面
And Jo, I can see your shoes under the couch.
好了  谁负责男生们
Ok, now, who's dealing with the boys?
西装在这里
Ok, we got suits.
戒指在这里
I got the rings.
婚誓在这里
And the vows.
那现在做什么
So...what do we do now?
敬阿拉里克·萨尔茨曼
To Alaric Saltzman,
今天以后  他这辈子
who after today, will have sex with
就只能跟一个女人做爱了
only one woman for the rest of his life.
真的  就一个
Seriously, just one.
今后连想都不能想了
You can't even look after this.
虽说神秘学研究教授
Not that chicks are throwing themselves
本来也不是很吸引女人  不过...
at an occult studies professor, but--
是啊  你还是趁她没改主意赶紧娶回家吧
Yeah, actually, you should probably lock this down while you can.
嗯  还记得你们不和的时光是多么美好吗
Yeah, you remember how great it was when you two were fighting?
抱歉  今晚满月
Sorry. Full moon tonight.
我特别想犯浑
Feeling extra dickish.
你又有什么借口
And what's your excuse?
怎么了
What? What is it?
婚礼杂务
Wedding day chores.
卡罗琳分配的
Courtesy of Caroline.
报应  天道自有轮回啊
Karma. Sweet, sweet karma.
男生们已经搞定了
Ok, the boys are officially taken care of.
新娘和伴娘都打扮好了
Bride and maid of honor are in hair and makeup.
我这就去场地收拾好他们搞砸的东西
I'm gonna head to the venue and fix whatever they're screwing up.
埃琳娜  捲发钳
Elena, the curling iron.
嗯  看到啦  卡罗
Yes, is, I see it, Care.
-好  -我是变成了人  但我不瞎
- Ok. - I'm human now, not blind.
也不是玻璃人
And I'm not fragile, either.
你不用对我那么小心翼翼的[踩蛋壳]
You don't have to walk on eggshells around me.
我需要啊
Uh, I do, actually,
因为如果你踩到了蛋壳
because if you walked on them,
就可能被割伤  可能会感染  可能会死
they could cut you, you'd get infected, and probably die.
知道吗
You know what?
鉴于我的运气
Given my luck,
这似乎的确有可能
that actually seems possible.
做活人的感觉如何
So what's it like now in the world of the living?
不一样了  我速度慢了
It's different. I'm slower.
过马路之前得左顾右盼了
I have to look both ways before crossing the street.
但这样不错  不用...
But it's nice to not--
做我那样的恶魔
Be a monster like me
关闭了人性  还杀人
who turns off their humanity and commits murder
而不是像个普通人那样面对丧亲之痛
instead of dealing with grief like a normal person?
我是想说不用成天戴日光戒指了
I was gonna say not to have to wear a daylight ring all the time.
对不起  埃琳娜
Look, I'm so sorry, Elena,
我之前说你不是人类
I was trying to hurt you
所以跟达蒙在一起也找不到真幸福
when I said that you would never truly be happy with Damon
只是想伤害你
because you weren't human.
而现在你变回了人类
And now you are,
我希望这不是因为我让你觉得
and I just hope that it's not because I made you think that
你的永生会很痛苦
you would be miserable for eternity.
卡罗  我自从成为了吸血鬼就一直想变回人类
Care. I've wanted to be human from the day I became a vampire.
而且  你是最不用跟我道歉了
Besides, I'm the last person that you need to apologize to.
谢谢  我想从比较轻松的那个开始
Thanks. I kind of wanted to start with an easy one.
可怕的赎罪之旅啊
The dreaded amends tour.
如果你看到了斯特凡  我正在躲他
If you see Stefan, by the way, I am avoiding.
我得先恢复我的生活
I just need to get my life in order first.
从我的朋友开始
Starting with my friends.
斯特凡不算朋友吗
Stefan's not a friend?
斯特凡  比较复杂
Stefan's...complicated.
我想挨个人恢复  最后到他
I just figured I'd work my way up to that one.
你没事
Well, you're in the clear.
他今天得应付达蒙
He's got his hands full with Damon today.
达蒙怎么了
What's wrong with Damon?
没什么  他就是说要跟我一起服用解药
Not much. He just said he would take the cure with me.
达蒙·塞尔瓦托吗
Damon Salvatore?
变成人吗
Human? I--
我简直无法想象
I can't even picture it.
嗯  我觉得他也无法想象
Yeah. Something tells me neither can he.
好啊  我做你的伴郎  里克
"Sure, I'll be your best man, Ric,
不过我要先跟最坏的人待在一起
but first, hang out with the worst men
好在你婚礼这天
so that my brother can kidnap me
被我弟弟绑架
on the day of your wedding."
你不是反正也讨厌婚礼的吗
Hey, don't you hate weddings anyway?
我更讨厌斯特凡操纵我的想法
I hate little Stefan mind games even more.
你如果想告诉我  我们究竟要去哪  请便
So any time you want to clue me in as to where the hell we're going.
得了  这是你做吸血鬼的最后几天了
Oh, come on. It's your last few days as a vampire.
我想跟哥哥好好聚聚
You can't blame me for wanting to spend
这不能怪我吧
some quality time with my brother.
看啊  我们到了
Ah, look. Here we are.
罗杰斯先生知道我们要来吗
Is Mr. Rogers expecting us?
你知道罗杰斯先生已经死了吧
You know Mr. Rogers is dead, right?
是啊  你如果不赶紧说明用意
Yeah, we're gonna be joining him in make-believe
我们也要无聊死了
if you don't get to the damn point.
我曾经在这栋房子里
So this is a house I lived in
重新开始过一段生活
during one of my many attempts to start over.
欢迎来到你的郊区噩梦
Welcome to your suburban nightmare.
你以为我没想好吗
You don't think I've thought this through?
我觉得你考虑的是跟埃琳娜共度一生
Well, I think you've thought about a life with Elena.
但你可能没想过邻居
I don't think you've thought about neighbors
按揭
or a mortgage or--
孩子
or kids.
我也说不好
I don't know.
或许不适合你呢
Might not be your thing.
放松  放松
Relax. Relax.
我不是来捣乱的
I'm not here to cause mischief.
每个捣乱的人都这么说
Said everyone who ever causes mischief.
我答应莉莉会来看她的
I told Lily I'd visit.
你这是恋母情结吗
Is this like some oedipus thing?
告诉你  无所谓了
All right. You know what? Doesn't matter.
抱歉  小女巫
Excuse me, little witch.
如果你觉得  我会让你
If you think I'm gonna let you--
这个专门搞破坏的人进来见另一个同类
a ruiner--in here to see another ruiner
而且还是在乔婚礼这天
on the day of Jo's wedding,
你就错了
you got another thing coming.
她孤单  饥饿
She's lonely and hungry.
她不能吸血
And she can't eat that.
我不是要喂她血
I'm not trying to feed her.
我只是想让她保持清醒
I'm trying to keep her sane.
那里面全是她熟悉的时代的歌曲
That is filled with loads of songs from the last era she knew.
我觉得能给她点慰藉
I thought it might bring her comfort.
如果你不是完全铁石心肠
If you're not a complete monster,
相信你一定会转交的
I trust you'll pass it on.
我想要回我的家人
I want my family back.
我只想要这个
That's all I've ever wanted,
让我家人回到我身边  这才是他们的归宿
to have my family back with me where they belong.
怎么回事
What?
她在念念叨叨说她的家人
She was rambling on about her family,
我就靠过去
and then I got close to her,
她就像个动物一样袭击了我
and she attacked me like an animal.
看来她已经达到了风干的彻底疯狂阶段
Sounds like she's reached the full-blown crazy stage of drying out.
你是说这完全是因为她在风干吗
You're saying this is all because she's drying out?
我很难解释那感觉多糟糕
It's hard for me to explain how awful it is,
但是的  你的头脑会开始欺骗你
but, yeah, your mind starts playing tricks on you.
你会看到幻象
You start seeing things and people.
过了疯狂的阶段呢
What happens when the crazy stage is over?
斯特凡说他有计划
Well, Stefan said that he has a plan,
帮她重回正轨
you know, to get her back on track.
那要放她出来吗
Does that plan involve letting her out?
因为他如果以为她会放弃自己的家庭
Because if he thinks she's giving up on her family--
她必须放弃
She has to.
邦妮  你已经毁掉了支配器
Bonnie, you already destroyed the ascendant.
如果有漏洞呢
What if there's a loophole?
我好怕
I'm dreading it,
但我觉得我该去穿婚纱了
but I guess I should think about putting the dress on.
出事了
Something's wrong.
不是婚纱吧
it's not the dress, is it?
告诉我不是婚纱
Tell me it's not the dress.
我们刚刚在讨论
We were just discussing the fact
地下室里锁着一个正在风干的吸血鬼
that there's a desiccating vampire locked in a cell
我们就在不到50英尺的地方准备婚礼
less than 50 feet from where we're getting ready.
她弄坏婚纱了吗
Did she do something to the dress?
婚纱没事啦
The dress is fine.
是我多心了
I'm just being paranoid.
好了  车来了  谁跟我们来
Ok. Truck's here. Who's coming?
卡罗琳用半威胁的语气
Caroline suggested in a semi-threatening way
叫我来搬装饰物
that I pick up the centerpieces,
依我的风格  感觉势必会搞砸的
which sounds like a Donovan screw-up waiting to happen.
我来吧
I'll come!
-谢谢  -嗯
- Thank you. - Yeah.
不是那儿  那里
No, not there. There.
再高点
Just a little bit higher.
那不叫一点了
Well, that's not a little, but--
我不擅长摆花吗
But I'm bad at flowers?
嗯  你早该知道了吧
Yeah. I assumed you knew that.
卡罗琳  为什么叫我来
Caroline, why am I here?
我试图杀你
I tried to kill you.
虽然我是关了人性  但我还是试图杀你
My humanity was off, but I still tried to kill you,
你是我的朋友  我很抱歉
and you're my friend, and I'm sorry.
说来有趣
That's funny.
虽然我们早就翻篇了
You and I moved on a while ago,
但被前任和她新男友折磨
but getting tortured by your ex and her new boyfriend
还是会让人伤自尊
is never good for the ego.
他不是我男友
He's not my boyfriend.
随便了
Whatever he is.
我都跟不上节奏了
I can't keep up.
你要知道我是绝不会那么做的
You have to know I would never do anything like that
都怪我...
if it weren't for--
没事啦  卡罗
You're good, Care,
如果你想弥补
and if you want to make amends,
就让我离开这里吧
let me get the hell out of here.
想得美
Nice try, ok,
如果我要结婚了  而圣坛却是那个样子
but if I were getting married at an altar that looked like that,
我不到一周就得离婚
I would be divorced in a week,
加把劲吧  洛克伍德
so come on, Lockwood.
下一排
Next row.
老实说  你还是自己做吧
Honestly, you should probably do that yourself.
丽芙  你怎么来了
Liv, what are you doing here?
你知道乔是我姐姐吧
You do know that Jo's my sister, right?
太好了  又能冰释前嫌了
Goodie! More amends.
喝杯酒会更好  烈酒
Drinks will help! Strong ones.
你看上去不错
You look good.
谢谢
Thanks.
最近怎么样
How are things?
挺好
Good.
伤势还没完全恢复吗
Still recovering from that injury?
什么伤势
What injury?
害得你只会吐单音节词的头部创伤
Whatever head injury turned you into a monosyllabic goon.
单音节词  大学辍学生还会念这么长的词
Monosyllabic. That's an awfully big word for a college dropout.
抱歉了  我难道还该留在惠特曼大学吗
Oh, I'm sorry. Was I supposed to stay at Whitmore
我的混蛋男朋友跟我说他再也不想见到我了
after my ass of a boyfriend told me he never wanted to see me again?
等等  你还生我的气吗
Hang on. You're mad at me?
我一周内先后失去了孪生弟弟和男友
I lost my brother and then my boyfriend in the span of a week.
你不向我寻求安慰
And instead of coming to me,
而是企图自杀
you tried to kill yourself.
我当时很伤心
I was hurt.
那也不是借口
That doesn't make it ok.
你还要就发火的问题教训我吗
You're lecturing me on flying off the handle?
这样吧
You know what?
我还是去外面等着吧
I'm gonna wait outside.
双子巫师团的婚礼会有很多巫师到场
Gemini wedding means big coven reunion heading this way.
埃琳娜说她在风干
Elena says she's desiccating
所以才那么疯狂  但是...
and that's why she's crazy, but--
是啊
Yeah.
她上周没在风干的时候就杀过两个人
She killed two people last week when she wasn't desiccating.
我知道这听上去很疯狂
I know this will sound crazy,
但我一直在做恶梦
but I've been having these nightmares
梦到她和卡伊
with her and Kai.
给
Here.
这是什么
What's this?
邦妮·贝内特如果有了预感
When Bonnie Bennett has a hunch,
是不容忽视的
you don't ignore it.
你觉得我们该怎么办
What do you think we should do?
我知道我们不该怎么做
I know what we shouldn't do--
让两个我们不信任的人处理她
leave her in the hands of two people we don't trust.
嗯  不错啊
Yeah, it's nice.
巴西硬木材
Brazilian hardwoods,
开放式隔间
open floor plan,
最新样式的厨房
updated kitchen.
你在做什么碾死动物呢
What kind of roadkill are you cooking in there?
鉴于你得像人类那样吃东西
Well, considering the fact that you actually have to eat as a human,
我想让你看看
I just wanted to give you a little taste
你的晚餐以后会是什么样
of what your dinner's gonna look like.
你不会做饭  埃琳娜也不会
You don't cook, Elena doesn't cook.
而且要工作带孩子  谁有时间啊
Who has time anyway with work and kids, right?
索尔斯伯利牛肉饼  开动吧  达蒙
Salisbury steak. Dig in, Damon.
你会需要体力  看这个
You're gonna need all that energy for these.
那是什么
Oh, yeah? What's this?
你的余生
That's just the rest of your life.
文件  这就是你的妙招
Paperwork? That's your big move?
我问问你
Let me ask you something.
你上次填写任何的文件是什么时候了
When was the last time you filled out paperwork of any kind--
报税  人寿保险  驾照
taxes, health insurance, driver's license?
全国上下哪个人不会啊
Every idiot in the country does it.
这东西能是问题吗
You think I'm gonna have trouble with this?
等你第一次遇到你不能杀  不能催眠的白痴
You will the first time you encounter some moron
就会成为问题了
that you can't kill or compel.
或许吧  那我就回家来
Maybe. Then I would just come home
从我漂亮的不锈钢冰箱里拿瓶酒出来
and pop a beer from my beautiful stainless steel refrigerator.
而你如果没有工作  就买不起这些
Which you won't be able to afford unless you have a job,
如果你要说你可以跟我借钱
and if you're about to say you can borrow money from me,
那是不行的
you can't.
这可不像好兄弟啊
Well, that's not very brotherly of you.
这就是好兄弟该做的
Actually it is. See,
因为我到时不会知道你在哪
I won't know where you live.
你身体里会流淌着解药
You'll have the cure running through your veins,
而我如果知道你在哪
and if I know where you are,
那别人就可以通过我找到你
then someone can use me to track you down
夺走你的解药
and take the cure from you
然后把你变成172岁的尸体
and turn you into a 172-year-old corpse.
怎么了  这点还没想过吗
What's the matter? Haven't thought that far ahead?
最终  消息会传开
See, eventually, word will spread,
你和埃琳娜就得逃跑了
and you and Elena will have to move away.
你们得与世隔绝
You'll have to isolate yourself,
不能与朋友家人待在一起
no friends, no family.
这就是你今后的生活了  达蒙
This will be your life, Damon.
你的地狱
This will be your hell.
你错就错在这里了  弟弟
Well, that is where you are wrong, my brother.
我的生活不会是这样
This will not be my life.
这才是
This will be my life.
埃琳娜对她想要的生活说得很清楚
See, Elena was pretty explicit about what she wanted.
这虽然不是特里贝克地区
Now this isn't tribeca.
我嫌纽约太挤了
New York's a little too crowded for me,
但这栋公寓在我所有的一间酒吧楼上
but it is above a bar that I own
还挨着一所医学院
next to a medical school.
在西北某处
It's in the northwest somewhere.
我倒是愿意告诉你地点
I mean, I'd tell you where it was,
但你显然是不想知道
but you made it abundantly clear you didn't want to know.
我去楼上看看
I'm gonna check out upstairs.
我喝三杯了  慢点说
I'm on my third glass, so speak slowly.
你知道我们都担心
You know how you and I were both worried
他没想清楚吗
that he didn't think this through?
他想得很清楚
He thought it through.
这是达蒙啊  不可能的
It's Damon. He didn't.
他真准备好了  埃琳娜
He's ready to do this, Elena.
他把你完美的人生都规划好了
He's got your perfect little life all planned out.
我也想跟他过完美的人类人生  斯特凡  真的
I want the perfect human life with him, too, Stefan, trust me,
但生活是不完美的
But life isn't perfect.
你还有几小时时间
Ok? Look. You have a few more hours,
再逼逼他  让他想通
so push him, make him see that.
记得你刚刚还想慢慢喝吗
Remember when you were pacing yourself?
是啊
I do.
但我刚刚才让我前男友
Right before I told my ex-boyfriend
想办法让我现男友
how to get my current boyfriend
放弃我们在一起的希望
to give up hope for our relationship.
如果我服下解药是个错误呢
What if I made a huge mistake by taking the cure?
你唯一的错误
The only mistake you made
就在于最后的那杯香槟
was that last glass of champagne.
我去煮点咖啡
I'm gonna go make some coffee
免得你栽在地上  掉到地球对面去
before you spiral through the earth to China.
好吧
Yeah, ok.
乔
Jo?
你没事吧
Are you ok?
乔
Jo!
乔  乔
Hey, Jo, Jo!
Jo! Jo!
医生拿到检测结果了
The doctor got the test results back.
孩子没事  你也没事
The babies are fine, you're fine.
他认为这只是
He thinks it was just--
惊恐发作
An acute panic attack
由压力和怀孕
brought on by stress, pregnancy,
和低血糖引发
and a severe lack of food.
嗯
Yeah.
你能不能做个好伴娘
What are the chances of you being an amazing maid of honor
不把这事说出去
and keeping this mortifying episode to yourself?
我不想让里克担心
I don't want to worry Ric.
当然了
Of course.
你不能告诉她我告诉你了
You can't tell her that I told you.
好吧  但我得见她
Ok. Fine, but I want to see her.
-得等到婚礼之后  -埃琳娜
- Not till the wedding. - Elena!
里克  如果说你该在什么地方相信迷信
Ric, if there's anywhere that you should be superstitious,
那绝对是神秘瀑布镇了
it's Mystic Falls.
好吧  但究竟怎么回事
Ok. Fine, but what happened?
医生认为是惶恐发作
The doctors think that she had a panic attack.
是不想嫁给我所以惶恐吗  这可好
As in she doesn't want to get married to me panic attack? Great.
不  是因为今天是她的婚礼
No, as in it's her wedding day
而且她还怀着一对儿孩子
and she has two small humans growing inside her
而且她又不能像你那样喝波本缓解紧张
and she can't self-medicate like you, bourbon breath.
抱歉  我看到她摔倒
Sorry. I just--I saw her fall,
我的第一直觉是瞬跑过去
and my first instinct was to vamp to her,
但又做不到
but I couldn't,
然后我看到她撞到了头
and then I saw her hit her head,
我想给她吸血鬼血
and I wanted to give her vampire blood,
我也不能
but I couldn't.
等等  你是后悔了吗
Wait. So are you having second thoughts?
没有  因为我又想
No, because then I thought,
人类会怎么做呢
"What would a human do?"
所以我打了911  送她去了医院
So I called 911, got her to the hospital,
让医生履行职责
and then I let the doctors do their job,
这感觉很有力
and it felt oddly empowering.
你怎么没说
Why didn't you tell me?
说什么
Tell you what?
重新成为人类是多棒的感觉
How amazing it feels to be human again.
我起初还担心这会让我的感官迟钝
At first, I was worried that it might take the edge off my senses,
但恰恰相反
but it's the opposite.
我觉得
I feel...
自己又和世界产生联系了
Connected to the world again.
我感觉
I feel...
有活力
Alive?
是啊
Yeah.
那是因为你的人生又有目标了
That's because your life has purpose again.
又有限了
It's finite,
这...
and it's...
是最棒的感觉了
pretty much the greatest feeling in the whole world.
我给你们调了很好喝的酒
I made you guys some amazing drinks
还加了点龙舌兰
with a little bit of tequila.
好吧  加了好多
Ok. A lot of tequila.
却只有你一个人
And there's only one of you.
你做什么了
What did you do?
我什么都没做
I didn't do anything.
他气冲冲地说
He said angrily.
什么都没变
Nothing has changed.
怎么  她换了件漂亮裙子
What? Because she walks in here
和新发型走进来
with a pretty dress and a new haircut,
我就该忘记她的行为吗
I'm supposed to forget how she acted?
不  你该像个大人那样跟她好好谈
No. You're supposed to talk to her like an adult
解决你们的问题
and work out your problems.
你根本不了解我们有什么问题
You don't know about our problems.
是啊  但我知道你的问题
No, but I know about your problems--
除非你不介意
Unless you're cool with
只在警校待两周
only making it two weeks in the police academy
然后就失去人生目标
and then having no purpose in life.
至少你跟她在一起时
At least when you had her,
你还很努力  泰勒
you were trying, Tyler.
你还跟我提感情建议
You're giving me advice about relationships
你今年和斯特凡都闹了些什么事啊
after all your Stefan drama this year?
帮帮忙  先理清你自己的生活吧
Do me a favor. Figure out your own damn life.
让我自己理清我的
Let me worry about mine.
斯特凡
你的努力值得称赞  斯特凡
Well, I applaud you for your effort, Stefan,
但未来生活展览之旅该结束了
but I think it's time for the "this is your life" tour to end.
地址你有了吗
You get the address?
有了  礼服也在车里
Yep. Tuxes are in the car.
-随时可以出发  -很好
- We're good to go. - Good.
对了  还有一件事
Oh, hey! Just one more thing.
又怎么了
Ohh. What now?
你是准备教我洗衣服
You gonna give me a lecture on laundry,
换机油  还有注意个人卫生吗
oil changes, personal hygiene?
-分手  -怎么了
- Breakups. - What about them?
我猜你还没想过这个  对吗
Well, I guess you hadn't really thought about that, right?
如果你和埃琳娜不是真的灵魂伴侣呢
What if you and Elena aren't really soul mates?
你知道我向来不在乎标签  弟弟
You know I'm not very big on labels, bro,
但我想这方面我们应该没问题
but I think we're pretty good on that front.
你听起来跟四年前的我一模一样
Ahh. Yeah. You sound like me 4 years ago.
知道吗  埃琳娜和我曾经也是灵魂伴侣
You know, Elena and me, we were soul mates, too.
说话小心点  斯特凡
Watch it, Stefan.
我只是实话实说
Hey. I'm just being realistic.
如果真的有了问题呢
I mean, what if something goes wrong?
你将一直是人类  与世隔绝
You're still human, still isolated,
孤身一人
still alone.
这不会发生的
Not gonna happen.
没错  因为情侣都会幸福一辈子
Right because couples stay together forever.
从不吵架  也不会伤害对方
They never fight, they never hurt each other,
更不会渐行渐远
they never drift apart.
我来让你看看
Let me show you.
你还没睡呢
You're still up.
今晚很辛苦吗
Rough night?
只是有点漫长
Just...long.
我一直告诉自己
I keep having to tell myself
只要再熬几年实习医生
a couple more years of residency,
我就能解脱了
and I'll be free.
过来坐  陪我喝一杯
Come sit, have a drink with me.
说实话  我有点累
I'm actually kind of tired.
我先去睡了
I'm gonna go to bed.
天哪  埃琳娜有工作  快来人救救我
Oh, god! Elena has a job. Somebody, help me!
这才是两年后的事
Oh, that's just two years in.
等你看看七年之后再说吧
Wait till you hit 7.
你好啊
Hello.
你醉了
You're drunk.
你对我不满  奇怪了
I sense judgment, which is odd.
不是你让我开酒吧的吗
You're the one that wanted me to own a bar.
我是想让你开酒吧  达蒙
I wanted you to own it, Damon,
不是每晚在那一醉方休
not pass out on it every night.
知道吗  至少那酒吧比你热情多了
Yeah? Well, that bar's a lot more affectionate than you.
我才结束实习医生的阶段  达蒙
I just finished my residency, Damon.
我得努力工作打造一份事业
I'm working my butt off to build a career.
是吗  我也在努力喝酒打造我的
Well, I'm drinking my butt off building mine.
如果你这么不开心  那就卖了酒吧
If you're that unhappy, then just sell the bar.
然后做什么
And do what?
我不在乎  达蒙
I don't care, Damon.
你想做什么都行
Whatever it is you want to do.
问题就在这里  埃琳娜
Well, that's the thing, Elena.
我不能做我想做的事
I can't do what I want to do
因为我想做的是彻夜狂饮
because what I want to do is drink all night
却能千杯不醉
without getting drunk,
像疯子一样飙车
drive my car like a psycho
而不用担心会死
without fear of death.
我想拧断别人的脑袋
I want to tear someone's head off
也没有人能拘捕我
without getting arrested.
没错  达蒙
You're right, Damon.
你不能再做这些事了
You can't do any of those things anymore.
因为你
Because of you.
我不能  都是因为你
I can't because of you.
你就说吧
Just say it.
这是个该死的错误
This was a damn mistake.
没错
You're right.
这是个错误
This was a mistake.
滚出我的意识
Get out of my head!
我知道你想干什么了
I see what you're doing.
你不是担心我会孤独一人
This isn't about me being alone.
而是担心你自己会孤独
This is about you being alone
当你失去了我  失去了埃琳娜
without me, without Elena.
你真自私  弟弟
Awfully selfish of you brother.
就算你和埃琳娜
Even if you and Elena defy
能排除万难
every single statistic
每一天每一刻都爱着对方
and stay in love every hour of every day...
你仍不能掌握生老病死
you still can't control life or death.
她是人类  随时都可能死
She's human. She could die at any moment.
如果没有了她  你的人生
What is your life gonna look like
会变成怎么样
without her?
你故意疏离我们的感情
So you make us drift apart,
让我们分手  然后杀了她
break us up, and then kill her?
这也太残忍了  弟弟
That's harsh, brother.
是她希望我残忍一点
She wanted me to be harsh.
这是她的主意
This is her idea, too.
真可笑
Well, that's funny
跟我最亲近的两个人
because the two people closest to me
却最能狠心伤害我
are the two most sadistic.
如果这么做  达蒙  你就会永远变成人类
You know, if you do this, Damon, you're human forever.
无论发生什么  你都无法回头
No matter what happens, there's no going back.
那你觉得我该怎么做
What do you think I should do?
问题就在这里  我没法告诉你
That's the thing. I can't tell you,
埃琳娜也没法告诉你
Elena can't tell you.
你不能为我或是为她这么做
You can't do this for me or for her.
你必须自己想成为人类
You have to want to be human for yourself.
抱歉  那边有人要酒
Oh, excuse me. They need some more drinks over there.
谢谢
Thank you.
乔呢  她
Hey! Where's Jo? Is she--
她很好  他们让她去休息了
She's fine. They discharged her.
很好  她可以去后门休息没人会打扰
Good. Well, there's a back entrance she can use that avoids being seen.
好的  我会告诉她
Ok. I'll tell her.
很好
Great.
斯特凡
Stefan.
我还是去等乔了
I'm gonna go wait for jo.
好
Ok.
我还不是很习惯看到人们被我吓跑
I'm not used to scaring people away.
人们见到穿晚礼服塞尔瓦托兄弟会不适应
People are uncomfortable around Salvatores in tuxes.
因为会让人们
It stirs...
心潮澎湃
Feelings.
埃琳娜又恢复人类的感觉了
Uh-oh. Elena's human again.
是不是又要换人了
Am I sensing another brother swap?
他和你一起来了吗
Is he with you?
没有  他需要时间思考
No. He needed some time to think.
这听起来不是很好啊
That sounds very ominous.
你不想让他服药  对吗
You don't want him to take it, do you?
那不是我的选择
Well, it's not up to me.
斯特凡  我不是他
Stefan, I'm not him.
你可以告诉我真实感受的
You can tell me how you really feel.
当然了  我是不希望他服药
Look. Of course, I don't want him to take it.
他是我哥哥
He's my brother.
一想到要失去他
The thought of losing him is--
我懂的
Yeah, I know.
那你觉得他会怎么做
So what do you think he's gonna do?
你不认识人类的达蒙
Well, you never knew Damon as a human.
他漫不经心
He was aimless,
总在寻找更多
always searching for something more,
人很好很热心
sweet and earnest to a fault
但他并不是个坚强的人
but never strong.
当他找到了自己才变得坚强
That came later when he found himself,
成为了现在的达蒙
when he truly became Damon.
他喜欢当吸血鬼
He loves being a vampire,
我只是觉得他没法放弃
and I just don't think he'll ever give that up.
她会杀掉我们的
She's gonna kill us.
我以为重点就在于
I thought the whole point of this
我们是要去控制住她
is that we were in control of her.
我不是说莉莉  我是说卡罗琳
Not Lily. Caroline.
婚礼还有一小时就要开始了
The wedding starts in an hour.
我们只要打晕她
All we have to do is knock her ass out
然后拖去锅炉房就行了
and drag her to the boiler room.
最多三十分钟
30 minutes tops.
邦妮
Bonnie.
肯定是恩佐把她放出来了
Enzo must have let her out.
我得赶紧警告大家
I have to warn everyone.
马特
Matt?
马特  你怎么了
Matt, what's wrong?
我没法呼吸了
I can't breathe.
好像有人掐住了我的脖子
It's like someone's crushing my throat.
你坚持住  我
Ok. Just hang on. I'll--
马特
Matt.
来杯茶  谢谢  伯爵茶
Tea, please. Earl grey.
什么风把你吹来了
And to what do I owe the pleasure?
我听说你本来要给我带一个
I heard you tried to bring me something called
MP3播放器
an, uh, MP3 player.
我还不知道那是什么
I'm not entirely sure what that is,
但我还是想感谢你一下
but still, I wanted to thank you.
然后他们就放你出来向我道谢了吗
And they let you out of your cell to do this?
当然不是
Of course not,
但我很有办法的
but I'm resourceful.
我是不是应该担心
Hmm. Should I be concerned
你要兴起一场腥风血雨了
about an imminent ripper binge?
事实上  不用
Actually, no, you shouldn't.
我成了开膛手是因为我失去了我的家人
I was a ripper because I lost my family,
但今天  我会找回他们
but today, I'm getting them back.
如果你是想偷偷约我出去
If you're trying to organize a secret rendezvous--
别担心  不是的
Don't worry. I'm not.
只是我的婚誓需要点帮忙
I just need help with my vows.
什么词能和战地止血钳押韵
What rhymes with battlefield clamp?
离婚行吗
Divorce?
你写的怎么样了
So how are yours coming?
别再套我的话了
Stop fishing for spoilers.
这里到处都是双子巫师团的人
You know, this place is crawling with Gemini.
你们的巫师居然有这么多人啊
Who knew there were so many of you?
因为在巫师团除了生孩子也没什么事干了
Well, there's not much to do in the coven other than procreate.
我爸爸没来吧
You haven't seen my dad, have you?
我还没见到  但你能
No, actually, but it's big of you
邀请一位谋杀你未遂的人真的很大度
to invite your attempted murderer to your wedding.
因为他会送贵重礼物
He gives really good gifts.
还有  不要对孕妇说
Oh, and never say, "Big of you,"
和大肚谐音的词
to a pregnant woman.
见不到你真的很郁闷
I hate that I can't see you right now.
真开心你为这郁闷
I love that you hate it.
待会儿见
See you soon.
拜拜
Bye.
也许我还是
Maybe I should just, uh,
放下礼物就走人
leave my gift and go then.
爸爸
Dad.
你怎么回来了
What are you doing back here?
你是我女儿啊
You're my daughter,
我...
And I, um--ahem--
我不指望你会同意
I don't expect you to say yes,
但是
but...
但如果我都不问你要不要陪你走红地毯
if I didn't at least ask to walk you down the aisle,
我自己都不能接受
I couldn't live with myself.
你在躲着我
You're avoiding me.
什么  没有  我才没有
What?! No. I'm not avoiding you.
我是在尽力组织好这一片混乱
I'm trying to organize this whole circus here.
你看到他们把酒水台放哪儿了吗
I mean, did you see where they put the bar?
卡罗琳
Caroline...
我们能聊聊吗
Can we talk?
好吧  我就直说了
All right. Just say it.
我错了  我太以自己为中心
I'm wrong, I'm making this about me,
我很自私
I'm being selfish.
不  抱歉  不想失去你哥哥
No. Sorry. Not wanting to lose your brother
不能算是自私
is pretty low on the selfish scale.
然而逼迫别人关闭人性...
Forcing someone to turn off their humanity on the other hand, that--
是啊  那就算得上是自私了
Hmm. Yeah. That's, uh-- that's way up there.
是啊
Yeah.
你恨我吗
Do you hate me?
不  我当然不恨你
No. Of course, I don't hate you.
但我不喜欢你处理问题的方式
That doesn't mean that I don't hate the way you handled things.
我也是
Well, that makes two of us.
我列了个清单
I made a list...
是自从我爱上你之后所做的所有事情
of, um, all the things that I've done since I fell for you.
是从去年夏天你搬走时开始的
It started last summer when you moved away.
我开始特别在意你去了哪儿
I started obsessing over where you were,
想知道你为什么不回我电话
wondering why you weren't returning my calls.
感觉被忽视时我就跟你说我恨你
I told you I hated you when I felt ignored,
因为在吻你而错过我妈妈的临终时刻
missed my mom's final moments because I was kissing you,
随后她过世了
and then she died...
卡罗琳
Caroline.
我只想要
And all I needed
你能告诉我  你对我也有所感觉
was for you to tell me that you felt something for me,
而你没有
and you didn't,
这对我造成了很深的影响
and it affected me so deeply that
以至于我做出了吸血鬼能做的最可怕的事情
I did the worst possible thing a vampire can do.
我关闭了人性
I turned off my humanity,
就在我以为我再也不能做出什么坏事时
and when I thought I couldn't do anything else,
还让你关闭了你的人性
I got you to turn off yours.
我原谅你
Well, I forgive you.
但问题就在这里  斯特凡
Yeah, but that's the point, Stefan.
原来的卡罗琳不会原谅我
The old Caroline wouldn't have forgiven me.
她会给我一耳光然后说
She would have smacked me and said,
"你到底在干什么"
"What the hell are you doing?"
我讨厌这样的感觉
I hate the way that this has made me feel.
那是因为你是一个失去控制的控制狂
That's because you're a control freak who's lost control.
我在你身边也会有这样的感觉
I feel the same way when I'm around you.
爱上一个人就是这样的
That's what falling for somebody is.
会很脆弱
It's being vulnerable.
是要...
It's...
放弃控制
giving up control.
我知道
I know...
但现在我的生活
But where I'm at right now in my life
伴随着内疚和悲痛
with the guilt and the grief,
控制是我仅剩的
control is all I have,
我觉得我没法放弃这一点
and I don't think that I can give that up.
伴娘裙不该会是
Isn't a bridesmaid's dress supposed to
让你看起来很奇怪吗
make you look like a freak of nature?
乔对我很客气
Jo went easy on me.
我跟斯特凡谈过了
I talked to Stefan.
他对我可不客气
He did not go easy on me.
显然  这是你的错
Apparently, that's your fault.
他的说法还是很具说服力的
His argument was pretty convincing.
我下定了决心
I'd made up my mind...
但之后
But then...
你毁了我的球
You ruined my ball!
你很幸运我没毁了你的脸
Well, you're lucky I didn't ruin your face!
进屋  把妈妈的车钥匙拿来
Go inside, get the car keys from your mommy.
我要去参加婚礼
I'm going to a wedding.
重新考虑
On second thought.
别忘了
Don't forget the--
剩菜
The leftovers.
我知道  你都说了三次了
I know. You told me 3 times.
40年  每一次
40 years, and every time,
"你记得拿剩菜了吗"
"Did you remember the leftovers?"
好像我变得年迈了似的
Like I'm getting senile or something.
我接受
I'm taking it.
我做吸血鬼已经很久了  埃琳娜
I've been a vampire for a long time, Elena.
这事情很有冲击力
It's been a blast,
但我会放弃吸血鬼的身份  只要能成为你的丈夫
but I would give it up in a second to be your husband,
你的配偶
your partner,
你孩子的父亲
father of your kids.
你不能因为我而服下解药
You can't take it just for me.
你和斯特凡都这么说
That's what you and Stefan keep saying,
但你们错了
but you're wrong.
我可以
I can.
我可以为了我们服下解药
I can take it for us.
好吗
Ok?
因为即使不能成功
Because even if it doesn't work,
即使一切都毁灭
even if all goes to hell,
即使我悲惨而孤独
even if I'm miserable and alone,
能和你拥有完美生活的丁点机会
the smallest chance at the perfect life with you
也远胜于没有你的永恒人生
is infinitely better than an immortal one without you,
我知道  埃琳娜
and I know this, Elena.
我爱你
I love you...
只要我有一口呼吸  我都会永远爱你
And I will love you until I take my last breath on this earth.
你在哪儿
Where the hell are you?
邦妮和马特已经失踪了
Bonnie and Matt are already M.I.A.,
现在你和达蒙也失踪
and now you and Damon?
你们什么毛病  这可是婚礼
What is wrong with you? This is a wedding.
这本该是乔的魔幻之夜
This is supposed to be Jo's magical night,
你们却要毁了它
and you are ruining it.
我们不等你们先开始了
We're starting without you.
这不好笑
This is not funny.
有点好笑
It's kind of funny.
听着  我不想告诉你
Uh, hey. Look. I don't want to tell you
该怎么进行婚礼但是...
how to run your wedding, but--
我们不等了
We're not waiting anymore!
告诉他们演奏音乐吧
Tell them to cue the music.
我觉得开始了
Um, I think it's starting.
什么  不
What? No.
几点了
What time is it?
卡罗琳来电
我的天  不不不  我们太晚了
Oh, my god. No. No, no, no. We're so late.
你是一直用小魔爪纠缠着我
Well, you're the one that couldn't keep your paws off of me.
达蒙  快把晚礼服穿上
Damon, put your tux back on.
在穿  在穿
I am, I am.
我希望是有够重要的
Well, I hope it was worth it.
实际上
Actually...
好恶心  现在不是时候好吗
Echh. Gross. Not the time, ok?
你们看到邦妮或马特了吗
Have you seen Bonnie or Matt?
还没到吗
They're not here yet?
去吧  去吧
Just go, go. Go, go, go.
好吧
Ok.
邦妮
Ugh. Bonnie.
Bonnie.
那是...
It was...
所以呢
And so?
看起来我要加入人类种族啦
Looks like I'm joining the human club.
今晚对我俩来说都是大日子
It's a big night for both of us.
我为你骄傲
I'm proud of you.
我也是  老兄
You, too, buddy.
欢迎各位亲属和朋友们
Welcome, family and friends,
在这个梦幻的夜晚
on this magical evening
来参加阿拉里克·萨尔茨曼
to the wedding of Alaric Saltzman
和乔赛特·拉夫林的婚礼
and Josette Laughlin.
乔赛特和阿拉里克已准备好各自的誓词
Josette and Alaric have prepared their own vows.
不可能
This can't be it.
这里没人
No one's here.
也许你的同伴给了你错误的地址
Perhaps your companions gave you the wrong address.
给我地址的不是他们
They're not the ones who gave me the address.
那是谁
Then who did?
我们俩现在都不该在这里
Neither one of us should be here right now.
我们这一辈子都在逃避命运
We've spent our lives dodging fate
挑战机遇
and beating the odds,
但因为我们的所作所为
but because we did,
我才能遇到你
I got to meet you,
最美丽
the most beautiful,
最好笑
hilarious,
最智慧的女人
and intimidatingly brilliant woman
此生唯一
I have ever known.
你激励了我
You inspire me.
你让我见识到  幸福
You've shown me that happiness
实际上是我生活中就可以拥有的
is actually something that I can have in my life.
因此
And so...
我发誓要和你在一起
I promise to be with you
爱你
and love you
和你一起躲避命运
and to dodge fate with you
此生不渝
for the rest of our lives.
乔赛特
Josette?
天哪  这样的誓言太难超越了
Oh, god. That's a tough act to follow.
这是我的誓言
Here goes.
阿拉里克·萨尔茨曼  你是
Alaric Saltzman, you are--
乔  怎么了
Jo? What is it?
乔  我的天
Jo? Oh, my god.
乔
Jo?
我的天  不
Oh, god. No!
-不  -不不不
- No! - No, no, no, no.
我的天  不不不
Oh my God. No, no no no.
我本打算等到"直到死亡将我们分开"
I was gonna wait till the "Death do us part" bit,
但似乎这样也恰好
but it seemed a little on the nose.
不是吗
Am I right?
想我了吗
Miss me?
不想吗
No?
好吧
Oh, well.
支持我们，欢迎购买VIP移除所有广告，具体：www.OpenSubtitles.org